Mss.B.G96 Mss.B.G96
American Philosophical Society
- Series Three: Correspondence with George John Romanes, 1887-1893; B G96.r; Gulick, John Thomas, 1832-1923
  - Letter to [George John] Romanes, Sept. 16, 1890; B G96.r; 7x6-1/2; Gulick, John Thomas, 1832-1923
    Hiigata, Japan, A.L. 8p. Draft. In pencil. (see Gulick papers.) Printed in part: Gulick. Evolutionist and Missionary; pp.438-439.
  - Letter to [John T.] Gulick, Dec. 9, 1890; B G96.r; 6x4; Romanes, George John, 1848-1894
    Oxford, A.L.S. 4p. (see J.T. Gulick. Correspondence with Romanes.) Concerning their views on evolution. Refers to Wallace. Printed in part: Gulick. Evolutionist and missionary...; p.440.
  - Letter to [John T.] Gulick, December 25, 1890; B G96.r; 7x4-1/2; Romanes, George John, 1848-1894
    Oxford, A.L.S. 4p.,end. (see J.T. Gulick. Correspondence with Romanes.) Concerning his fight with Wallace on evolution. Printed in part: A.Gulick. Evolutionist and missionary...;pp.287-288.
  - Letter to [George John Romanes;], 1890; B G96.r; 10-1/2x8; Moulton, J. Fletcher (John Fletcher), 1844-1921
    ca. L. 21p. Copy. (see Gulick papers.) Concerning Gulick's paper.
  - Letter to [George John] Romanes, Feb. 17, 1891; B G96.r; 8x5; Gulick, John Thomas, 1832-1923
    Osaka, A.L. 19p. Draft. In Pencil. (see Gulick papers.) Printed: Gulick. Evolutionist and Missionary; pp.441-445.
  - Letter to [George John] Romanes, Feb. 20, 1891; B G96.r; 8x5; Gulick, John Thomas, 1832-1923
    A.L.S. 1p. Draft. (see Gulick papers.) Lists corrections and addenda for his paper concerning Moulton.
  - Letter to [George John] Romanes, March 7, 1891; B G96.r; 8x5; Gulick, John Thomas, 1832-1923
    A.L.S. 2p. Draft. (see Gulick papers.) Printed: Gulick. Evolutionist and Missionary; pp. 288-289.
  - Letter to J[ohn T.] Gulick, Osaka, Japan, March 26, 1891; B G96.r; 5-1/2x3-1/2; Romanes, George John, 1848-1894
    Oxford, A.L.S.with initials on postal card. 1p. and add.,end. (see J.T. Gulick. Correspondence with Romanes.) Concerning evolution and his fight with Wallace. Printed in part: A.Gulick. Evolutionist and missionary...; p.450.
  - Letter to [John T.] Gulick, May 19, 1891; B G96.r; 10x8; Romanes, George John, 1848-1894
    Oxford, A.L.S. 6p. (see J.T. Gulick. Correspondence with Romanes.) Concerning their works on evolution and their disagreement with Wallace. Concerning Darwinism and religion. Printed in part: A.Gulick. Evolutionist and missionary...; p.295.
  - Letter to [George John] Romanes, May 25, 1891; B G96.r; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Gulick, John Thomas, 1832-1923
    Osaka, A.L.S. 1p. Draft. (see Gulick papers.) Printed: Gulick. Evolutionist and Missionary, pp.450.
  - Letter to J[ohn T.] Gulick, Osaka, Japan, June 24, 1891; B G96.r; 5-1/2x3-1/2; Romanes, George John, 1848-1894
    Oxford, A.L.S.on postal card. 1p.and add. (see J.T. Gullick. Correspondence with Romanes.) His and Galton's views on the evolution of some mice. Printed: A.Gulick. Evolutionist and missionary...;pp.450-451.
  - Letter to J[ohn T.] Gulick, Osaka, Japan, July 2, 1891; B G96.r; 5-1/2x3-1/2; Romanes, George John, 1848-1894
    Oxford, A.L.S.with initials on postal card. 1p. and add. (see J.T.Gulick. Correspondence with Romanes.) Concerning questions about rats. Printed: A.Gulick. Evolutionist and missionary...; pp.451-452.
  - Letter to [George John] Romanes, Oct. 6, 1891; B G96.r; 4-1/2x3-1/2; Gulick, John Thomas, 1832-1923
    Osaka, A.L.S. 2p. Draft. (see Gulick papers.) Printed in part: Gulick. Evolutionist and Missionary; p.295.
  - Letter to J[ohn T.] Gulick, Osaka, Japan, Nov. 12, 1891; B G96.r; 5-1/2x3-1/2; Romanes, George John, 1848-1894
    Oxford, A.L.S.on postal card. 1p.and add., end. (see J.T. Gulick. Correspondence with Romanes.) Concerning a publication. Asks how he withstood the earthquake.
  - Letter to G[eorge] J[ohn] Romanes, Oxford, Nov. 21, 1891; B G96.r; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Moulton, J. Fletcher (John Fletcher), 1844-1921
    L. 3p. Copy in typescript. (see Gulick papers.) Objections to Gulick's hypothesis.
  - Letter to [John T.] Gulick, Dec. 5, 1891; B G96.r; 7x4-1/2; Romanes, George John, 1848-1894
    A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see J.T. Gullick. Correspondence with Romanes.) Forwards publication. Printed in part: A.Gulick. Evolutionist and missionary...; p.452.
  - Remarks on Mr. Moulton's reasonings and calculations, sent to [George John Romanes;], 1891; B G96.r; 10x8; Gulick, John Thomas, 1832-1923
    ca. A.D.S. 13p. Draft. (see Gulick papers.) Printed: Gulick. Evolutionist and Missionary, pp.446-449.
  - Christianity and the evolution of rational life, Jan. 5, 1892; B G96.r; Gulick, John Thomas, 1832-1923
    A.D.S. 8p. Draft. Partly in pencil. (see Gulick papers.) Printed: Gulick. Evolutionist and Missionary; pp.289-293.
  - Letter to [George John] Romanes, Jan. 30, 1892; B G96.r; 8x5; Gulick, John Thomas, 1832-1923
    Osaka, A.L. 6p. Draft. (see Gulick papers.) Printed: Gulick. Evolutionist and Missionary, pp.452-453.
  - Letter to J[ohn T.] Gulick, Osaka, Japan, March 29, 1892; B G96.r; 5-1/2x3-1/2; Romanes, George John, 1848-1894
    Oxford, A.L.S.with initials.on postal card. 1p. and add. (see J.T.Gulick. Correspondence with Romanes.) Concerning publication of photographs of Darwin, Wallace, etc.
  - Letter to J[ohn T.] Gulick, Osaka, Japan, June 2, 1892; B G96.r; 5-1/2x3-1/2; Romanes, George John, 1848-1894
    A.L.S.with initials on postal card. 1p.and add. (see J.T. Gullick. Correspondence with Romanes.) Concerning evolution and Darwin. Printed in part: A.Gulick. Evolutionist and missionary...;pp.453-454.
  - Letter to [George John] Romanes, Aug. 4, 1892; B G96.r; 8x5-1/4; Gulick, John Thomas, 1832-1923
    A.L. 4p. Draft. In pencil. (see Gulick papers.) Printed: Gulick. Evolutionist and Missionary, pp.454-455.
  - Letter to J[ohn T.] Gulick, Osaka, Japan, Oct. 27, 1892; B G96.r; 10x8; Romanes, George John, 1848-1894
    Oxford, Typed L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see J.T.Gulick. Correspondence with Romanes.) Concerning his publication of Darwin and Darwinism. Printed in part; A. Gulick. Evolutionist and missionary.. pp.455-456.
  - Letter to [George John] Romanes, Dec. 27, 1892; B G96.r; 8x5-1/4; Gulick, John Thomas, 1832-1923
    Osaka, A.L.S. 1p. Draft. (see Gulick papers.) Sorry he is ill. Grants permission to publish letter on insects.
  - Letter to J[ohn T.] Gulick, Osaka, Japan, June 16, [1893]; B G96.r; 5-1/2x3-1/2; Romanes, George John, 1848-1894
    Oxford, A.L.S.on postal card. 1p.and add. (see J.T.Gulick. Correspondence with Romanes.) Asks for negative for photograph of self for purposes of reproducing it.
  - Letter to John [T.] Gulick, Osaka, Japan, Oct. 9, 1893; B G96.r; 5-1/2x3-1/2; Romanes, George John, 1848-1894
    A.L.S.on postal card. 1p.and add. (see J.T. Gulick. Correspondence with Romanes.) Asks for autograph for purpose of reporducing it. Printed: A.Gulick. Evolutionist and missionary...; p.309.
  - Letter to [George John] Romanes, Dec. 6, 1893; B G96.r; 8x5; Gulick, John Thomas, 1832-1923
    A.L.S. 2p. Draft. 2p.of signatures of "John T. Gulick" (see Gulick papers.) Printed in part: Gulick. Evolutionist and Missionary; p.310.
  - Address Sheet to John T. Gulick, Jan., 1897
    Envelope addressed to Gulick with stamps. Pencil note: "These were sent to Mrs. Romanes through the publishers of her life of Romanes..."
  - Letter to [George John] Romanes., Undated; B G96.r; 8x5; Gulick, John Thomas, 1832-1923
    A.L.S. 2p. Draft. (see Gulick papers.) Introduces a young student of natural history who is capable of understanding the "Wider and truer philosophy of evolution which you are seeking to propagate."